Guide to the Cindy Sheehan Papers TAM.715
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Cindy Sheehan Papers
1982-2023
1998-2016
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Sheehan, Cindy
TAM.715
7.03 Linear Feet in 10 manuscript boxes, 1 half manuscript box, 1 flat box, and 4 oversized flat boxes
3.09 Gigabytes in 37 computer files
3 websites in 3 archived websites.
Cindy Sheehan (b. 1957) is an activist, author, former congressional candidate for California's 8th District, and former gubernatorial candidate for the state of California. The Cindy Sheehan Papers record Sheehan's involvement in the post September 11, 2011 anti-war peace movement, the Gold Star Families for Peace, Camp Casey, her 2008 congressional campaign, and her 2014 gubernatorial campaign. The collection consists of Cindy Sheehan's notebooks; newspaper clippings about Sheehan's anti-war efforts and the Iraq War; copies of her own monographs; photographs from protests, Camp Casey, and her gubernatorial election; as well as artifacts such as campaign pins and protest banners. The collection also includes video and audio memorials for her deceased son (U.S. Army Specialist Casey Sheehan), protest and election brochures, anti-war posters, magazines detailing Sheehan's political activities, as well as correspondence to Sheehan, the Gold Star Families for Peace, and Camp Casey.
Conditions Governing Access
Box 11 contains sensitive financial documents and materials protected under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPAA) that are restricted. The electronic file "Correspondence - Lori Ann Zarlenga -- Medical Records" contains material protected under HIPAA and is also restricted. The remaining materials in the collection are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Cindy Sheehan in 2016. The accession number associated with this gift is 2018.088.
http://cindysheehanssoapbox.blogspot.com/ was initially selected by curators and captured through the use of Archive-it in 2017. The accession number associated with this website is 2017.029. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In 2020, https://cindysheehanssoapbox.podbean.com/ was added. The accession number associated with this URL is 2021.053. In 2022, https://cindysheehan.substack.com/ was added. The accession number associated with this URL is 2022.087.
Take Down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.
If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.
If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.
Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Arrangement
Materials in this collection have been grouped together thematically and then arranged alphabetically.
Biographical Note
Cindy Sheehan (b. 1957) is an activist, author, former congressional candidate for California's 8th District, and former gubernatorial candidate for the state of California. Sheehan's anti-war activism stems from the death of her eldest son, U.S. Army Specialist Casey Austin Sheehan (1979 - 2004), who was killed in combat during the Iraq War. In 2005, Sheehan garnered national and international media attention when she established an anti-war encampment, later named Camp Casey, outside of President George W. Bush's ranch in Crawford, Texas. Camp Casey existed for five weeks, attracting the voices and physical presence of supporters and detractors alike.
Sheehan is also a founding member of the Gold Star Families for Peace. Established in 2005, this organization is an affilite of Military Families Speak Out and supports families whose loved ones were killed in action during the Iraq War. In addition to her activism, Sheehan has written several books --Dear President Bush,Peace Mom,Not One More Mother's Child,I Left My Marbles in San Francisco: The Scandal of Federal Electoral Politricks, and The Obama Files: Chronicles of an Award-Winning War Criminal-- all of which discuss her political views as a part of her anti-war campaigning.
In 2008, Cindy Sheehan ran against Nancy Pelosi for a seat in Congress, but was unsuccessful, having received only 16% of votes. In 2012, she was selected as the Vice Presidential nominee for the Peace and Freedom Party. In 2014, Sheehan participated in California's gubernatorial election and lost having only received 1.2% of the statewide vote.
Starting in 2009, Sheehan began hosting a weekly radio show where she interviewed individuals including Hugo Chavez and Howard Zinn. Sheehan also maintains a blog called "Cindy's Soapbox."
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted. Born-digital materials have not been transferred and may not be available to researchers. Researchers may request access copies. To request that material be transferred, or if you are unsure if material has been transferred, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Scope and Contents
The Cindy Sheehan Papers record Sheehan's involvement in the post September 11, 2011 anti-war peace movement, the Gold Star Families for Peace, Camp Casey, her 2008 congressional campaign, and her 2014 California gubernatorial campaign.
Cindy Sheehan's involvement in the post September 11, 2011 anti-war peace movement roughly spanned from 2004 to 2016. The collection includes personal notes from Sheehan's anti-war activism; photographs of her participation in peace protests; a video recording documenting her protest near President George W. Bush's ranch in Crawford, Texas; and letters of support from fellow anti-war protests. The collection also contains letters sent to the Gold Star Families for Peace, Camp Casey, and official White House correspondence sent to the Sheehans after their son, U.S. Army Specialist Casey Sheehan, was killed by enemy action during the Iraq War, as well as an audio memorial for Casey Sheehan.
Published versions of Sheehan's books Dear President Bush, Peace Mom, Not One More Mother's Child, I Left My Marbles in San Francisco: The Scandal of Federal Electoral Politricks, and The Obama Files: Chronicles of an Award-Winning War Criminal are included within the collection.
The Cindy Sheehan Papers document Sheehan's 2008 congressional campaign in the form of flyers and notebooks. Her 2014 California gubernatorial campaign is documented in the form of sample voter ballots, voter information packets, photographs, brochures, official documents, flyers, campaign materials, as well as correspondence.
The collection also includes a blog containing clips from news shows, articles, and interviews relating to issues of war, independence, and government, both in the United States and abroad. The blog consists of entries dating from 2009 to the present.
Separated Materials
During processing, a large selection of commercially published books, DVDs, and CDs were removed from the collection. Several digital video files were also removed from the collection due to copyright.
Anti-war demonstrations -- United States -- 21st century; Iraq War, 2003-2011 -- Peace.; United States--Politics and government.; Anti-war demonstrations.; Peace and Freedom Party (Calif.); Governors -- Election; Notebooks; Photographs.; Books.; Correspondence.; Newspaper columns.; Political posters.; Blogs; Sheehan, Cindy
- 22nd Kelly McGillis Classic (Special Guest - Cindy Sheehan), 2013 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 2014 Gubernatorial Election (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
- 2014 Gubernatorial Election - Donation Reports, 2008-2009 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- 2014 Gubernatorial Election - Report of Receipts, 2008-2009 (Box 11, Folder 2-3)
- 2014 Gubernatorial Election - Pin (Box 1, Folder 4)
- AAFIA - A National Call for an Innocent Woman (Dr. Aafia Siddiqui), undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Addicted to War: Why the U.S. Can't Kick Militarism, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Anti-War Flyers and Brochures, 2007-2009 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Anti-War Pins, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Anti-War Posters, 2001, 2006 (Box Shared Tamiment 079, Folder 34)
- Arthur J. Jones, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Articles Written by Cindy Sheehan, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Asian Pacific Islander American Public Affairs Association - 6th Annual API Forum, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Beyond Iraq - Building the Beloved Community, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Birthday Card to Cindy Sheehan, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Breaking the Silence - Facing the Real Costs of War Organizing for a Just Future, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Calendars, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Camp Casey - Correspondence, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Camp Casey - Diary, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Camp Casey - Florida Notebook, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Camp Casey - Phoenix, AZ Banner, 2005 (Box 12)
- Camp Casey - Photograph, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Camp Casey - Portraits, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Camp Casey - Poster, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Camp Casey - Property Deed, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Campaign Against Pelosi Notebooks, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Carol Troyer-Shank Notebook, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Casey's Legacy by Daniel Dupuis, 2007; cuid36462 (Box Electronic records, E-records TW_TAM_715_ER_1)
- Casey Sheehan - Grave Photograph, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Casey Sheehan - Notebook Honoring Service, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Casey Sheehan - Photograph, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Cindy for Congress - Photographs, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Cindy Sheehan 2008 Campaign Flyer (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Cindy Sheehan's Birth Day Certificate, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Cindy Sheehan's Soapbox - Correspondence, 2013-2014 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Cindy Sheehan Speeches, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
- "Close Guantanamo" Postcards, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Code Pink Decorative Pin, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Columbus, Ohio Vigil Photographs, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Common Ground Relief, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Congressman Charles Rangel, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, 2004-2014 (Box 3, Folder 12-14)
- Correspondence - Linda Auxer, 2006 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Correspondence - Lori Ann Zarlenga, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Correspondence - Lori Ann Zarlenga -- Legal Papers, 1998, 2000-2001, 2006-2007; cuid36465 (Box Electronic records, E-records TW_TAM_715_ER_2)
- RESTRICTED Correspondence - Lori Ann Zarlenga -- Medical Records, 2004-2005; cuid36466 (Box Electronic records, E-records TW_TAM_715_ER_6)
- Correspondence - New Hampshire, undated (Box Shared Tamiment 080, Folder 16)
- Correspondence - State of Utah to Cindy Sheehan, undated (Box Shared Tamiment 150, Folder 13)
- Correspondence - Sunflower Sketch from Mark Smith, undated (Box Shared Tamiment 080, Folder 17)
- Correspondence - U.S. Government to Sheehans about Death of Casey Sheehan, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Crawford Peace House, undated; cuid36464 (Box Electronic records, E-records TW_TAM_715_ER_4)
- Crawford Peace House - Correspondence, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Crawford Peace House - Photographs, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Current Biography (article about Cindy Sheehan), 2007 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Dear President (Cindy Sheehan) (Arabic), undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
- "Dear President Bush" (Cindy Sheehan), 2005 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Directory of Cindy Sheehan Supporters, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
- The Eagle's Own Plume - Poems on Iraq, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Eugene V. Debs Award Honoring Cindy Sheehan, 2016 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Eyes Wide Open - An Exhibition on the Human Cost of the Iraq War, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Eyes Wide Open Exhibit Photographs, 2005 (Box Shared Tamiment 080, Folder 18)
- Global Women's Rights Award, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- "Greetings from Camp Casey" Postcard Poster, undated (Box Shared Tamiment 150, Folder 14)
- Gold Star Families for Peace - Correspondence, 2006-2007 (Box 4, Folder 13, Box 5, Folder 1-4)
- The History of the Bush Presidency in Cartoons (includes cartoons about Cindy Sheehan), 2005 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Holistic Lifestyles Institute New College, 2012-2013 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Houston Peace and Justice Center Awards, 2007; cuid36463 (Box Electronic records, E-records TW_TAM_715_ER_3)
- I Left My Marbles in San Francisco (Cindy Sheehan), 2013 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Impeachment and Trial Notebook, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Inspire: Princeton Theological Seminary Magazine (article about Sheehan), 2005 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- "La Nobile Causa", 2005 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Learning Journey in Detroit, 2012 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Lebanon Banner, undated (Box 12)
- Legendaria Magazine (article about Cindy Sheehan), 2005 (Box Shared Tamiment 080, Folder 19)
- Mamma Pace (Peace Mom Italian Edition) (Cindy Sheehan), 2006 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- "Messages to Cindy" Notebook, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Michael K. Green, 1998, 2006-2007 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Mid South Peace and Justice Center, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Military Personnel - Reporting additional Servicemember Demographics Could Enhance Congressional Oversight, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Military Voices Against Endless War and Occupation, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Mothers Acting Up (MAU), 2006 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- "Mother to the Lost Innocents", 2001 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Myth America Tour, 2009 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1982-2016 (Box 7, Folder 3, Box Shared Tamiment 150, Folder 15-17, Box Shared Tamiment 142, Folder 12)
- Nightline - Iraq: Why Stay? Ticket, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Not One More Mother's Child (Cindy Sheehan), 2005 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Notebooks, 2006-2009 (Box 7, Folder 6-8, Box 8, Folder 1-4)
- Notebook and Loose Notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
- The Obama Files (Cindy Sheehan), 2015 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Peace House by Cheryl Frances, 2006 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Peace Not Poverty, 2005 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Peace Prayer Sculptor Aiqiu Hopen - Photographs, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Peacemaking, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- People Magazine (article about Cindy Sheehan), 2005 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Photographs, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Power to the People Certificate to Cindy Sheehan, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Press List for Cindy, 2006 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Protest Bumper Stickers, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Protest Photograph, 2006 (Box Shared Tamiment 080, Folder 20)
- Ray O'Light Newsletter, 2011-2012, 2014-2016 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Ron Paul, 1999, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- SACALT - Sacramento's Alternative Magazine (article about Cindy Sheehan), 2013 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Sing Shalom! New Prophet Voices, 2006 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- "Take Me Home" - A Sampler of American Artists for Peace, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Tales from the White Dog Caf, 2005 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Thomas Merton Award Dinner, 2005 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Tikkun Magazine, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Time Magazine - A Year in Review (article about Cindy Sheehan), 2006 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Tour de Peace, 2013 (Box 9, Folder 19)
- United States of America v. Cindy Sheehan (Court of Appeals), 2007 (Box 9, Folder 20)
- U.S. Citizens for Peace and Justice, undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
- Veterans for Peace, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- The Vigil - 26 Days in Crawford, Texas (forward by Cindy Sheehan), 2005 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Violation of US Citizen's Human and Constitutional Rights, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Voices of a People's History of the United States, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- A War in Iraq and the Requirement of Moral Certainty (Center for Christian Nonviolence), undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
- War is a Racket (Smedley D. Butler, forward by Cindy Sheehan), 2003, 2010 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- War Tax Resistance - A Guide to Withholding Your Support from the Military, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- White Privilege Conference, 2009 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Archived Websites, March 2017-April 2023; 3 websites in 3 archived website. (Box Electronic records)
  Appraisal
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored with the permission of the content owner. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://cindysheehanssoapbox.blogspot.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  Scope and Contents
  Websites for Cindy Sheehan's blog and online radio show, called the Soapbox. The blog dates back to 2009, but capture of the website began in 2017. Topics touched on by the radio show and blog include anti-war activism, United States militarism, environmental activism, war tax resistance, critique on President Barack Obama (including publicity for her book the Obama Files), nonviolent intervention, American imperialism, healthcare reform, Women's March on the Pentagon, establishment politics, and local politics in California. The radio show was also occassionally hosted by Irene Sanchez, Matt Sedillo, and Dakotah Lilly. It also includes the Revolutionary Organization of Labor (Ray O'Light) newsletter. In 2022, Sheehan stopped publishing on the Blogspot blog and began publishing on Substack, a newsletter platform. The substack contains episodes of her podcast, her video series with Dakota Lilly titled Shee-Lilly, and blog posts related to anti-capitalism and the anti-war movement.
  During the COVID-19 pandemic, Sheehan published personal accounts of her experience with the pandemic and misinformation about the coronavirus.
  Additionally, multiple posts on her Substack include transphobic language.